Preliminary Guide to the Luther Brady papers, MS2147.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Luther Brady papers
1965-2004
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Brady, Luther W.
MS2147.UA
43 Linear Feet 32 record center boxes
Luther W. Brady, MD, one of the world's foremost oncologists, is Hylda Cohn/American Cancer Society Professor of Clinical Oncology and Professor in the Department of Radiation Oncology at MCP Hahnemann University School of Medicine, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Dr. Brady received his undergraduate and medical education at George Washington University (AA'44, BA'46, MD'48). Dr. Brady's papers include article reprints, research files, notes, correspondence, meeting minutes, and programs. Materials date between 1965 and 2004, with the bulk dating between 1975 and 2000. This collection is unprocessed. Please see Special Collections staff for assistance.
Arrangement
Collection is unprocessed and material is in order as received. Please see Special Collections staff for assistance.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is unprocessed and may not be open for research. Please see Special Collections staff for assistance.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Dr. Luther Brady, 2006 (Accession 2006.002, 2006.003, 2006.028, 2006.054)
Scope and Contents
This collection is minimally processed and may not be available for research. Please contact Special Collections for more information.
Biographical / Historical
Luther W. Brady, MD, one of the world's foremost oncologists, is Hylda Cohn/American Cancer Society Professor of Clinical Oncology and Professor in the Department of Radiation Oncology at MCP Hahnemann University School of Medicine, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Former Chairman of the Department of Radiation Oncology and Nuclear Medicine at Hahnemann University, Dr. Brady stepped down in 1996, having built, during a distinguished tenure, a department reputed for its teaching excellence and innovative approaches in the treatment of cancer. Dr. Brady was born in North Carolina and received his undergraduate and medical education at George Washington University (AA'44, BA'46, MD'48). He received post-graduate training in radiology and radiation oncology at the U.S. Naval Hospital in Bethesda and in Philadelphia, at Jefferson Medical College and the Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania. Dr. Brady has been an active member of the GW Alumni community. He served as an Alumni Trustee from 1995 until 2001, served on the Centuries Campaign Committee in 1996, and is a current member of the Medical Alumni Association Board of Directors. He received a Distinguished Alumni Achievement Award in 1991, received the Society Medal from the Board of Trustees in 1995, and is currently a GW Trustee Emeritus.
Medicine; Oncology
- UP0001 (Box 1)
  - Malignant Tumors of the Eye - JE Lahaniatis, LWB, J.E. Freire, JA Shields, CL Shields, TE Yaeger, ACS Clin. Onc. (Hall), 3rd Edition, Chapter 29 Final, June 1999-February 17, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Radiation Therapy" - G. Mieszkalski, LWB, T. Yaeger, R. Chace for ACS Textbook of Clin. On., 3rd Ed., Chapter 8c; "Monoclonal Antibody: - Howard Ozer, MD, ACS Textbook of Clin. Onc., 3rd Ed., June 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Basis for Major Current Therapies for Cancer" - TE Yaeger/LWB; for ACS Textbook in Clin. Onc., Chapter 8A, 3rd Ed., April 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ACS Textbook of Clinical Oncology Editorial Board Meeting, Atlanta Airport, Atlanta, GA, 3rd ed., March 16, 1998-2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Head and Neck Cancer: A Multidisciplinary Approach, 2nd E. -- Harrison/Sessions/Hong, Lippincott WW, Cancer of the Orbit and Ocular Structures: Radiation Therapy and Chemotherapy Mgmt." Freire JE, LB, Chapter 32, March 2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Radioimmunotherapy as a Novel Trtmt. Regimen: I-125 Labeled Monoclonal Antibody 425 in the Trtmt. of High Grade Brain Gliomas," T. Quang & LWB (For IJROBP consideration), January 6, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Brachytherapy in the management of uveal melanoma. In: Radiotherapy of Inraocular and Orbital Tumors, 2nd revised Ed., SagermanRH, AlbertiWE (eds), by FreireJE, BradyLW, PetrovichZ, YoussefA, ShieldsJA, ShieldsCL. Medical Radiology: Radiation Oncology Series. Chapter 5, Pages 33-44. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, New York., 2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Plaque radiotherapy in the management of selected orbital malignancies. Preliminary Observations." ShieldsJA, ShieldsCL, FreireJE, BradyLW, KomarnickyLT. Accept for publication in: Opthalmic Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, September 2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Radiation Effects on the Eye" - LWB, TE Yaeger (6/99) to Prof. Alberti and Robert H. Sagerman, Md, eds. in Spring, 2001, June 1999 - 2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Combined Plaque Radiotherapy & Transpupillary Thermotherapy for Choroidal Melanoma.."-C Sheilds, Chao..., June 15, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Radiology -- Reflections in Rad. Onc. for Athony V. Proto, M.D., Editor (Drs. S. Levitt/R. Parker/W. Powers/LWB) "Radiation Oncology - The United States Contribution of the Lasy Years of the 20th C." Radiology, April 2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "A Tribute to Dr. Jerome Vaeth," by LWB, Front Radiat Ther Oncol, Vol. 35, 2001, pp. IX (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Phase III trial of External Beam Rad. Ther. with or without Thymosin in Adv. Non-Small Cell Lung Ca," Asbell, Seydel, LWB, Mohuiddin, Weigensberg, Montesano. IJRO submitted about 9/00 by Dr. W. Sause, September 2000 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Plaque radiotherapy for uveal melanoma: Long-term visual outcome in 1106 consecutive patients," ShieldsCL, ShieldsJA, CaterJ, GunduzK, MiyamotoC, MicailyB, BradyLW. Arch. Ophthalmol. Vol 118: 1319-1228, September 2000. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Immunotherapy for Primary Brain Tumors" - by J. E. Lahaniatis/LWB for Prof. Z. Petrovich, disk Microsoft Word 6.0/95, February 17, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Radiation Treatment for Benign Disease" - JE Lahaniatis, F Farzin, LWB, W Serber, TE Yaeger - JL Meyer's Book, June (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Orbital Pseudotumo" - LWB/TE Yaeger/ JE Lahaniatis; for J.E. Meyer's book, Front.Rad.Ther.& Onc., Karger, September 1999 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Hemangiomas" - LWB/TE Yaeger/JE Lahaniatis, for Dr. J.L. Meyer's book, Front.Rad.Ther & Onc., Karger, September 1999 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Age Related Macular Degeneration: Wet Type: - LWB, JE Freire, TE Yaeger - for JL Meyer's Book, June 1999 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Corporization of Health Care in the United States" - LWB, Pennsylvania Rdiological Society, May 15, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Age-Related Macular Degeneration: New Aspects of Treatment Mtg., 2/13/99, Hamburg, Germany (Prof. Alberti) Current Treatment Concepts, Medical Radiology Radiation Oncology, Alberti/Richard/Sagerman - editors Spring-Verlog, February 13, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Disease in Frontiers of Rad.Ther. and Onc., Vol 35 1999 June 14, Karger, Switzerland-Basel, June 14, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Morbidity following Rad.Ther.: 3-D vs 2D Rad. Ther, Trtmt Planning & Trtmt Delivery to Prostate,..Lahaniatis, LWB, RA Brutus (Dr. M. Molls, Munich, Germany, 3/99), March 1999 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Survival following enucleation v plaque radiotherapy in statistically matched subgroups of patients with choroidal melanomas: Results in pateints treated between 1980 and 1987," AugsburgerJJ, SchneiderS, FreireJ, BradyLW, Graefe's Arch Clin Exp Opthalmol. 237: 558-567, 1999. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Radiation Complications & Tumor Control after Plaque Radiother. of Choroidal Melanoma with Macular Involvement"- K Gunduz, CL Shields, JA Shields, J Cater, JE Freire & LWB (5/99) in Am J Ophthalmol 1999; 127: 579-589 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Radiation Retinopathy Following Plaque Radiotherapy of Posterior Uveal Melanoma" GunduzK, SheildsCL,, Shields JA, Cater J, Freire JE, Brady LW, Arch Ophthalmol, 117: 609-14, 1999. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - MABs in the Trtmt of Metastatic Ca to the Liver: Updated Report of a Pilot Study Includ Leukoopheresis, B Hill, T Minard, LWB, August 1997 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Philip Rubin, M.D., Editor, IJROBP Festschrift, Fall, 1997 (6/97), June 1997 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Radiation Therapy for Macular Degeneration" - LWB, Freire, Longton, etc. (Dr. P. Rubin's Festschrift, June 4, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Radiotion Oncology in the Third Millennium," for RADIOLOGY (Dr A. Proto) LWB/S. Levitt, August 7, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Plaque Radiotherapy in the Mgmt of Posterior Uveal Melanoma with Extraocular Extension" - Gunduz, CL Shields, JA Shields, J Cater, LWB, August 1998 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Choroidal Hemangioma," - Drs. BS Hill, LWB, C Hernandez, JJ Augsburger, JE Freire, May 1998 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Intra-arterial Coronary Irradiation in the Prevention of Restenosis after Percutaneous Transluminal Coronary Angioplasty: A Review," W Longton, L Farber, B Costleigh, D Diamond, B Lee, LWB, C Perez, C Miyamoto, B. Micaily, J Freire, March 31, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "Long-term survival in posterior uveal melanoma after enucleation v plaque radiotherapy" - JJ Augsburger, Z Correa, JE Freire, LWB (for consideration in Ophthalmology), November 1997 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "Plaque Radiotherapy of Macular Choroidal Melanoma," K Gunduz, C Shields, J Shields, J Cater, J Freire, LWB., October 31, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - External radiother. in macular degeneration: technique & preliminary subjective response. LWB/Freire/Longton/Miyamoto/Augsburger/Brown/Micaily/Unda. Internal Medicine 5:00-00. 1997 (Pisa Italy, 10/19-21/98), Prof. Angelo Carpi, October 19-21, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Intra-arterial coronary irradiation in the prevention of restenosis after percutaneous transluminal coronoary angioplasty: a review. W Longton/D Diamond/B Costleigh/B Lee/Lwb/C Perez/C Miyamoto/B Micaily/J Freiree, Internal Medicine 5:00-00, 1997 (Prof. Angelo Carpi--2nd Int'l Congress Vase Endothelium...& 5th Int'l Congress on Advances in Mgmt. of Malignancies), Pisa, Italy, October 19-21, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Chapter 36 - "Nonsurgical Mgmt of Orbital Tumors," J Freire, LWB, DePotter, Shields J/C, Augsburger, Longton, January 1998 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 8th Edition, Clinical Oncology: A Multidisciplinary Approach for Primary Care Physicians and Students (Taimi Marple, Ed) LWB/Merrill Solan, MD --chapters on Skin Cancer and Malignant Melanomas for 8th Edition, June 2, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "Detection of Infrequent Cells in Blood & Bone Marrow by Flow Cytometry" by Leon WMM Terstappen, March 1997 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Skin Cancer --Merrill J. Solan, MD/LWB, 8th Ed, Clinical Oncology: A Mulidiscipl.. Taimi Marple, Ed., WBSaunders Co., August 26, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Malignant Melanoma - Merrill J. Solan/LWB, 8th Ed., Clinical Oncology: A Multidiscpl. Tami Marple, Ed., WBSaunders Co., August 26, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Clinical Oncology, Edito-P. Rubin, MD, Skin Cancer Chapter to be done by LWB due 9/1/1997, September 1, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- UP0002 (Box 2)
  - "Treatment of metastic carcinoma of the prostate," H. Goethuys, L. Baert, H. Van Poppel, etc. (Zpetrovich - 4/97?), April 1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Rad. Ther. in the Magnagement of Temporal Bone Chemodectomas," Costleigh/Longton/Micaily/Miyamoto/LWB/Farzin/Freire, March 1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - External Radiotherapy in Macular Degeneration: Technique & Prelim. Subjective Response-LWB, J. Freire, W. Longton, c. Miyamoto, J. Augsburger, G. Brown, B. Micaily, R. Unda--Sent to Prof. Carpi, Pisa, February 7, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Intra-arterial Coronary Irradiation on Prevention of Restenosis after Percutaneous Transluminal Coronary Angioplasty: A Review--by W. Longton, D. Diamond, B. Costleigh, B. Lee. LWB, c. Perez, C. Miyamoto, B. Micaily, J. Freire (sent to Prof. Carpi 2/7/97, Pisa), February 7, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - MS - Freire JE, Brad LW, et al. "Tumors of the Orbit" Book Chapter (Louis Harrison MD), January 27, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Prophylactic" Retinal Irradiation is Ineffective in Preventing Appearance of New Retinoblastoma Tumors in Previously Uninvolved Retina, JC Hernandez, C Shields, J Shields, B Micaily, LWB, 10/96, to be in CANCER, October 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Head & Neck Cancer: A Multidisiplinary Approach, Chapter 36 "Nonsurgical Mgm of Orbital Tumors," L.B. Harrison, et al., November 30, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Trtmt. Related Complications for Bladder Carcinoma: Radical Surg. v. Bladder Preserving Techiniques," B. Costleigh, W Longton, LWB, C Miyamoto, JE Freire, B Micaily, F Farzin (sent to Dr. Petrovich for book, 11/11/96, November 11, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Endowed Professorships - IJROBP, September 1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Ext. Radiotherapy in Macular Degeneration: Technique & Prelim. Subjective Response: J. Freire, WA Longton, C. Miyamoto, LWB, et al, IJRO, May (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cancer of the Prostate Book by Petrovich, Baert, Brady, MEDICAL RADIOLOGY< Spring, January 20, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Carcinoma of the Prostate," Petrovich et al, Med. Radiology, February 26, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Redubulking in conjunction with 125 MAB 425 Trtmt in Mgmt of Primary Clioblastoma Multiforme" - Miyamoto, et al. sent to Radiation Oncology Investigations Clinical and Basic Research (Dr. Schmidt Ullrich), August 1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Editorial: "Radiother. for age-reltd. mac. degeneration: prelim. results of a potentially new trtmt" - Berson et al., IJRO BiolPhy (by LWB) and Edit. for Freire, J Md, June 5, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - External Radiother. in Mac. Deg.: Technique & Prelim. Subjective Response, J Freire, W Longton, C Miyamoto, LWB, Augsburger, G Brown, B. Micaily, R Unda, IJRO Biol Phys, Vol. 36, No. 4, p. 857-860, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Editorial: "Response of the Normal Eye to High Dose Radiotherapy" - Parsons et al., Oncology by LWB, June 5, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Cervical Interstitial Brachytherapy" by WA Longton, B Micaily, LWB (Prof. Helmut Vahrson), February 21, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Retionoblastoma after Chemoreduction & Irradiation: Prelim. Results" - J Freire et al. Berlin Germany Symp. 5/96 (Dr. Wiegel); 1st International Symposium on Radiation Therapy for Ocular Tumors, May 1996 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "Cancer of the Prostate: Brachytherapy Techniques," - LWB, Mtg. with Dr. Ptrovich, Chat. cela Bretesche, France, July 6, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "125 I Plaque Therapy for Uveal Melanoma: analysis of the Impact of Time & Dose Factors on Local control" - ARS Mtg, Paris France, Cancer, J. Quivey, L. Snelling, LWB, May 1995 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Seminars in Surgical Oncology, Drs. J. Frank Wilson, B. Micaily, LWB, April 1995 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "Biliary Tree Malignancies" by chung K. Lee, MD, Bennett R. Barrios, MD & Haraldur Bjarnson, MD UNiv of MN 7/29/96 - for Seminars in Surg. Onc., July 29, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "Brachytherapy in Surgical Oncology" - LWB/Wilson/Micaily/Erickson, August 1996 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "The Physics & basic Parameters of Brachytherapy" - Sem. in Surg. Onc., by Eric J. Lee, M. Sc. & Martin S. Weinhous, Ph.D., May 30, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - "High & Low Dose Rate Remote Afterloading: A Critical Comparison" by Colin S. Orton, Ph.D. - Seminars in Surgical Oncology, September 30, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - D.J. Brenner, MD - Radiation Biology in Brachytherapy, undate (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - B. Erickson MD & J.F. Wilson MD: Clin. Indications for Brachytherapy, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - L.B. Harrison, MD - Applications of Brachytherapy in H/N Cancer, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - W.R. Bodner, MD - Brachytherapy and Pancreatic Cancer, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - The Esophagus - by Dr. Micaily et al, for Seminars in Surg. Onc., September 27, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - J.R. White, MD - Carcinomas of the Breast, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - P.J. Eifel, MD - Gynelogical Neoplasm, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "Interstitial Implantation of Gynecologic Malignancies" - by Beth Erickson, MD & Michael Gillin, Ph.D., Med. Coll. of WI, recv'd 7/31/96 for Sem. in Surg. Onc., July 31, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - From Dr. Freire for your review of articles for "Seminars in Surgical Onc." (Primary Ocular Tumors), undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Sylvester, D.J., Interstitial Implantation, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Bizhan Micailly, Female Urethra, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - The Role of Brachytherapy in Adult Soft Tissue Sarcomas, Basil S. Hilaris, M.D./William R. Bodner, M.D./Constance A. Mastoras, rec' 7/11/96, July 11, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Erickson - Biliary Tree Malignanacies, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - S. Nag, MD, B. Erickson, MD - Interstitial Brachytherapy Procedure for Brain Tumors, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
- UP0003 (Box 3)
  - The Changing Role of Rad. Onc. in CA Man. by LWB. June 1983 CA 54:2506-2514 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "The Invisible Cancer Cure" Reader's Digest, April 1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Proton beam irradiation of uveal melanomas: results of a 5 1/2 year study" - Gragoudas, Goitein, Verheyett, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - RTOG/Phas I/II Co60/Iodine125/Ir192, pl. rx pos. uveal melanoma (eye)LWB/JS/JA/JD, August 4, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mesothelioma - Role for Radiation Therapy, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bone Metastasis LWB (2)Memo - Rad Ther. J. Carpenter MD, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Hyperbaric Oxygen/Cervix, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Brady et al - Radiation Ther. for Stage II Ovarian Cancer, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Brady et al. - Radiation Therapy for Intracranial Metastatic Neoplasia, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Brady - Treatment of Metastatic Disease of Nervous System by Radiation Therapy, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Pinealoma Paper, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Shocker - Preoperative Radiation Therapy in the Treatment of carcinoma of the Rectum and Rectosigmoid (Philadelphia Medicine), undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Brady, Blessing, Radiotherapy, Chemotherapy, and Combined Therapy in Ovarian Cancer, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Factors Influencing The Results of Definitive Irradiation in Inoperable Non-Oat cell CA of Lung (LWB), undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Brady-Croll - Role of Bone Scanning in cancer Patient, July 1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Honda - Radiopharmaceuticals for Pancreatic Tumors, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Honda - 75Se-Selenomethionine in Pancreatic Neoplasia, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Pineal Tumors, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Key to Use for Glossies, Emi's & Brain SX's, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Carcinoma of Pancreas LWB, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Management of Ewing Sarcoma LWB, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Presidential Address, Ca of the Breast - A Time for Caution-ARS, Las Vegas, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Brady - Internal MAMMARY Lymphoscintigraphy in the Breast (editorial - International Journal of Radiation Oncology), June 30, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Brady - cancer of the Breast Treatment Today, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Wallner et al - Sub-total Mastectomy & Rad. Ther in Def. Managment of Breast Malig., undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Brady - The Tole of the Physician in Diag. & Treatment of Breast Cancer (Phila. Med), undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Brady - Cancer document, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Brady - Carcinoma of the bladder (Phila., Medicine), March 1977 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Cancer is a Curable Disease - L. W. Brady, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Brady - Grubbe Lecture, Role of the Radiologist in Dx. & Trt. of Ca of Breast, October 20, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Brady - The Role of the Radiologist in the Diagnosis & Treatment of Carcinoma of the Breast, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Brady - Cancer of the Breast, Role of Rad. RX After Mastectomy, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Brady -- Cancer of the Breast-A Time for caution (ARS PResidential Addresss-April 25, 1977, Las Vegas) (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Commentary on Extranodal Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma (NHL)-Drs. Markoe & Brady (to be published), undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - "Modern Radiation Oncology" Volume II (Primary Ocular Tumors & Mesothelioma, Lymphoma GI), undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Primary Liver Cancer in Man, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Seminars - Jan 1983, Interstitial Radionuclide Lymphobcintigraphy, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Neuro-Oncology, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Brain Mets: Randomized Clinical Tr. etc. J.M. Kurtz, R. Gelber, L.W. Brady, M.D. (I.J.R), undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Radiotherapy Trials in Head & Neck Cancer--Brady, Marcial, Davis, Venice, Italy, October 1983 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - [Untitled], undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Extra-Nodal Lymphoma, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Malignant Lymphoma of the GI Tract - LWB, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Erskine Lecture - Atlanta, November 28, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- UP0004 (Box 4)
  - [Untitled], undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - PPRO 4th Edition, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - PPRO, 4/e Editors Meeting, Lippincott Williams Wilkins, Philadelphia, Washington Sq. Conf. Rm., February 21, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Principles and Practice of Radiation Oncology (PPRO), 3rd Edition, April 1995 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Chapter for Chao's Red Handbook "Radiation Oncology: Management Decisions" by K.S. Clifford Chao MD, Carlos A. Perez MD, Luther W. Brady MD, Lippincott Williams & Wilkins, 2001, 2e (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Rad. Onc.: Management Decisions, 2nd Edition, K.S. Cliff Chao MD, Carlos A. Perez MD, LWB MD, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Radiation Oncology: Rationale & Management Techniques (small textbooks on Rad. Onc.) Drs. Cliff K. Chao, C.A. Perez, LWB, 7/95, J.B. Lippincott; Radiation Onc..: Management Decisions, 6/96, July 1995 & June 1996 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The changing Role of Radiation Oncology in cancer Management, by LW Brady. Ca-A Cancer Journal for Clinicians, Vol. 33, No. 2, March/April 1983. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - In Memoriam (James W.J. carpender, MD, 1911-1982) by LW Brady, reprinted from RADIOLOGy, vol. 146, No. 2, pg. 564, Feb. 1983, copyright by RSNA., February 1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - A New Technique for the Trtmt of High Grade Gliomas of the Brain, by LWB, Quang T, Emrich J, Class R. (abs) Proceedings of the Advances in Management of Malignanncies Seventh Intern'l Congress, Biomedicube & Pharmacotherapy, Vol. 56, N0. 7:359. September 2002. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Bone Metastases, by LWB. (abs) Proceedings of the Advances in Management of Malignancies Seventh International Congress. Biomedicine & Pharmacotherapy, Vol. 56, No. 7, 36. September 2002. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Editorial, by LW Brady, Am J Clin Oncol (CCT) 26 (4): 323-324, 2003, Lippincott Williams & Wilkins, Inc., Philadelphia (Dr. Davide E. Wazer, new Editor of AJCO on 1/1/2004) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "Radioimmunotherapy as a Novel Trtmt. Regimen: 125I-Labeled Monoclonal Antibody 425 in the Trtmt. of High-Grade Brain Gliomas," TS Quang & LWB, Int. J. Radiation Oncology Biol. Phys., Vol. 58, No. 3, pp. 972-975, 2004, Elsevier Inc., Printed in the USA. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- UP0005 (Box 5)
  - Book, The Management of Head & Neck Cancer, James E. Hamner, III, D.D.S, Ph.D. 8/83, Springer-Verlag, 7/84, August 1983 & July 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Computed Brain and Orbital Tomography, Wiley (Gonzalez), undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Bedwinek, John M., MD - Treatment of Stage I & II Aderoca of Breast By Tumor Excision & IRradiation, May 1981 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Brady - Biologic Basis for Combined Modality Therapy, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Changing Role of Rad. Onc. in Ca Management - abstract for American Cancer Soc., May 26, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "Impact of Irradiation Technique & Tumor Extent in Tumor control...Non-Oat Cell Ca Lung" Brady, etc. - Cancer, June 1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Schocker, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)